Looking back at the distributions we found for the number of dogs I see,
بالنظر إلى التوزيعات التي وجدناها عن عدد الكلاب التي أراها،
we can mark the values of our five number summary like this.
يمكننا وضع علامة على قيم ملخص الخمس أعداد هكذا.
If we take just these marks,
إذا أخذنا هذه العلامات فقط،
this makes a common plot for data known as a box plot.
هذا ينشئ مخطط شائع للبيانات المتاحة يعرف باسم box plot.
Though I prefer a histogram in most cases,
على الرغم من أني أفضل المدرج التكراري في أغلب الحالات،
a box plot can be useful for quickly
إلا أن box plot يمكن أن يكون مفيدًا لإجراء مقارنة سريعة
comparing the spread of two data sets across some key metrics,
لانتشار مجموعتين من البيانات على مستوى بعض المقاييس الرئيسية،
like our quartiles, and the maximum and minimum.
مثل الربيعيات وأقصى وأدنى قيمة لدينا.
From both the histogram and the five-number summary,
بالنظر إلى كل من المدرج التكراري وملخص الخمس أعداد،
we can quickly see that the number of dogs I see on
يمكننا أن نرى بسرعة أن عدد الكلاب التي أراها في
weekends varies much more than the number of dogs I see on weekdays.
في عطلات نهاية الأسبوع يتنوع بشكل أكثر بكثير عن عدد الكلاب التي أراها في أيام الأسبوع.
We can also visualize the distance from here to here as the range,
يمكننا أيضًا تصوير المسافة من هنا إلى هنا باعتبارها النطاق،
while the distance from here to here is the interquartile range.
بينما المسافة من هنا إلى هنا تكون المدى بين ربعين.
There are lots of useful metrics we can get from these box plots.
يوجد الكثير من القياسات المفيدة التي يمكننا الحصول عليها من box plot.
But what if we want to compare the spreads of these distributions without having to carry
ولكن ماذا لو أردنا المقارنة بين انتشارات هذه التوزيعات بدون الحاجة إلى حمل
around all five of these values for each distribution?
كل هذه القيم الخمس لكل توزيع؟
What if I wanted just a single value to be able to compare the two distributions spreads?
ماذا لو أردت قيمة فردية فقط حتى أكون قادرًا على مقارنة انتشارات التوزيعين؟